Archana.G.S Data Scientist

Portfolio Linkedin Upwork Github Published paper

Milpitas,CA 669 231 9980 archanags001@gmail.com

Data Scientist with over 4 years of experience, specializing in machine learning and artificial intelligence. Demonstrated success in creating machine learning models, conducting in-depth data analysis, and applying problem-solving skills. Eager to contribute my expertise to the dynamic and challenging field of AI.

EXPERIENCE

Data Scientist — Freelance (January 2019 - PRESENT) Upwork

- Achieved Top Rated Plus freelancer badge, ranking in the top 3% of Upwork talent
- Collaborated with 9 clients to understand their company needs and devise data-driven solutions.
- Built a churn prediction model using ML, reducing churn by 18%. Segmented customers based on behavior in subscription-based models, improving retention with personalized engagement strategies.
- Developed a real-time anomaly detection system for financial transactions using PyTorch and PySpark, improving fraud detection rates by 15%.
- Designed and developed a News search tool leveraging LLM and Langchain technologies, enhancing the efficiency of information retrieval and analysis.
- Efficiently managed Azure Databricks, executed ETL, and developed ML models for small and large datasets(125GB, 1B rows), automated scheduling, tracked experiments, implemented Auto ML, and maintained resource efficiency

Data Scientist — Wonder Chrome (December 2021 -December 2024)

- Conducted A/B testing experiments to assess the effectiveness of various promotion strategies, resulting in a remarkable 24% increase in revenue.
- Developed machine learning models using scikit-learn to optimize pricing strategies, leading to a substantial 12% boost in profit.
- Led full data lifecycle: collection, cleaning, feature engineering, modeling, validation, and dashboard/report creation.
- Proficiently developed complex SQL queries, procedures, and reports using Redshift, Sagemaker, SQL, and Python to meet diverse client needs.
- Developed a Large-scale multi-label text classification model using Tensorflow and Keras to enhance text analysis capabilities.

Artificial Intelligence Engineer intern —Uniquify Inc(August 2021-October 2021)

- Led training and development of neural networks using TensorFlow, optimizing models for enhanced accuracy and efficiency.
- Conducted comprehensive experiments with TensorFlow scripts and analyzed results to enhance model performance and understand framework dynamics.
- Played a key role in debugging and improving an automation framework for neural network and TensorFlow scripts, streamlining workflows and ensuring reliable model training.
- Developed advanced image processing and segmentation algorithms to solve complex problems, contributing to project success.

Data Analyst — Centrige Inc (February 2020 - January 2021)

- Leveraged analytical and technical expertise to provide actionable insights and proposals, driving business improvement strategies.
- Designed and implemented a range of predictive models, including classification and forecasting models, using various machine learning tools to solve complex business challenges.
- Created interactive dashboards using Tableau and Power BI to communicate insights to diverse stakeholders.

SKILLS

Programming Languages:

Python, R, Core Java, Basic JavaScript

Database & Data Storage: SQL, MongoDB

Machine Learning and DeepLearning: TensorFlow, Keras, CNN, RNN, PyTorch

Natural Language Processing

(NLP): NLP techniques, Hugging Face, Langchain, Transfer learning,SpaCy, BeautifulSoup

Computer Vision: OpenCV, Transfer learning,YOLO, VGG16, ResNet

Cloud Services: AWS, Azure

Data Visualization Tools:

Matplotlib, Plotly, Seaborn

Data Processing & Analysis:

Excel, Elasticsearch, Logstash, Kibana

Big Data: PySpark

Dashboard Development:

Power BI, Tableau, Retool, Dash, Streamlit

EDUCATION

Master of Technology in Electronics with specialization in Signal processing

GPA: 4.0

Bachelor of Technology in Electronics and communication Engineering **GPA: 3.5**

WORK ELIGIBILITY:

EAD(Employment Authorization Document)